We talked about simple loops yesterday, we talked about four loops had a loop over each
item in a list.
List comprehension are one of those incredible features of Python that I think have been
making their way into other programming languages slowly over time.
They let you take a kind of a four loop and condensate it down into just one statement.
In a way that's actually pretty readable.
So we'll start with list comprehension and let's say I had my list of names, so just a list
of three items, everyone who's typing along, you can use whatever names you want.
Earlier, I wanted to build a new list that had maybe all the lower case names in it.
So I know that if I call, if I say string dot lower, it'll give me the lower case, if I say
string dot upper, it'll give me the upper case.
Okay, let's say I wanted to do upper case names.
Let's say I wanted to like shout them, reading them, you're shouting know that, you know,
these names are kind of really important.
So before I would make my list of upper case names and I would go through in a four loop,
right four name in names, I would say that the upper case name would be equal to name dot
upper, and then what action would I need to take next to build up my list of upper names
with these values?
How do we add to the end of a list, a pen?
So I would say upper names dot a pen and my upper case name, okay.
If we look in our upper names now, we'll see that we've looped through this list, we've
taken some action on it, right, but this is a lot of code and it's a pretty common programming
paradigm.
We do this type of programming all the time.
And so Python came up with a really handy shortcut for it.
To do a list comprehension, we start with the list syntax, so those square brackets.
And then, as you're kind of getting used to these, I find that the order really trips
people up.
And so I tend to basically write mine backwards, I think about what do I want to loop over
and I type that first.
So what were we looping over in our four loop?
Yeah, so I would say four names and names.
So that's the second half of our list comprehension.
Now move your cursor back to the beginning and place it right to the right side of that
first opening bracket.
The first part of the list comprehension is the action that we want to take.
So what was I doing with my name and the previous example?
Yeah, I was making it uppercase.
So here on the left hand side, I would say name dopper.
What result do we get when we run this?
That's right, a list of uppercase names, pretty useful, right?
We can, let's say we wanted to build a list of squares, right?
What function can we use in Python to generate a list of numbers in a sequence?
Range.
Range, right?
So quick recap of range.
If we call range without doing any sort of looping over it, we'll see this range
object.
It's because each item in it is generated on the fly, which is great, right?
It's great for performance, great for memory.
As we're learning, if we want to peek inside of range, just maybe we forget the syntax.
Quick note here for everyone who's not paying attention, like don't call range on a huge list
of numbers and call list around it because Nina told you so because that is not what I'm saying.
So if we want to peek inside of a range, we can call list on it, right?
So range with just one number will go up to that number, but not inclusive, so exclusive.
If we call range with two numbers, this first number is the starting number.
The range will be inclusive of the starting number, exclusive of the ending number.
And the third argument to range is a step.
So if I wanted to go through all the even numbers, or I'm sorry, not all the even numbers,
I wanted to go from one to four and add to each time I would get one and three, so that's how
range works.
Let's say I wanted to make a list comprehension that went through all of the numbers from
one to zero to five and printed out the square.
So I would say a four number in range, I wanted the numbers from zero to five, what range
would I need to, what value would I need to put in range, so this is what we're going to
loop over in our list comprehension.
And then moving back to the start of the line, Windows users, I don't know, Mac users
control a might help you get your line to the start, or your cursor to the start of the line.
If I wanted to do the squares, I would just say, you know, number number.
That's quickly all of our squares.
We can return a list of any of the other types that we've talked about.
In our first example, we saw strings, in our second example, we saw a number.
Let's take a look at a more complicated data type.
Let's say I wanted to return a list of tuples.
And the way that I would do that, so I would, you know, I have my names variable here.
I would make my list comprehension.
I'm going to loop over the name and names.
And what I want to return is a tuple.
So I'm going to put those parentheses around it.
I want a tuple that has the string length in it, for example, along with the length of the
name.
How do we get the length of a string?
With length, really?
Yeah.
That's right.
Don't forget an extra parentheses here, and I would get the length of my name.
So any variable that's on the right side of this four statement, that's available for
us to use in the left side of this equation.
Yesterday we used tuple unpacking to loop through two items that once, for example, if we
were looping over a list of tuples.
So call this one's comprehension.
And I get the word length followed by the length of each string.
One last thing I want to show with split and join.
I've showed you kind of fstrings, right?
So let's say the name is Nina.
And my fstring starts with an f.
They can say the name is followed by name.
If I wanted to do the same thing for a list of names and print them out in comma separated
string, I can do that with a join, right?
So if I just had kind of my one string here, it would be kind of funky, because it's
not a list.
You can pass a list comprehension into join, right?
Join takes a list.
So I can say four names in names like I did before.
And I can just go to the right, put my cursor to the right of that opening bracket.
And I can put an fstring in here and say name is name.
So I'm just putting some of these pieces together.